

Louis Kiesewetter

O Home: Semperstraße 29, Top 21, 1180, Wien, Austria

Email: louis.philippe.kiesewetter@gmail.com **\ Phone:** (+43) 67761040574

Date of birth: 25/10/1995 **Nationality:** German

ABOUT MYSELF

I'm a data enthusiast who loves transforming numbers into meaningful insights and have been solving complex problems with data-driven solutions for many years. Growing up across multiple cultures taught me adaptability and resilience, skills I now bring to highpressure environments with ease. I aim to spread a positive and friendly atmosphere wherever I go, driving collaboration and innovation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Finmatics GmbH

City: Wien | **Country:** Austria | **Business/sector:** Financial and insurance activities

[01/07/2022 - Current] **Data Scientist**

At Finmatics, I am an integral part of the Data Science team, working together to ensure the scalability and reliability of existing and new data processes within an Agile framework. My main responsibilities include:

- Implement machine learning prediction pipelines, ensuring robust real-time predictions for over 1,000,000 daily predictions
- Integrate large language models into production environments, delivering measurable benefits to customers
- Handle end-to-end backend development, maintaining full feature accountability from initial development through post-production release
- Improve model accuracy through continuous retraining and maintain alignment with state-of-the-art Al approaches
- Self-deploy microservies and maintain key metrics such as processing time

Toolkit:

Python, Django, PostgresQL, Elastic Stack, Azure ML, Weaviate Vector Databases, Multimodal Large Language Models, Docker, Sentry, Git, Angular

Georg Neumann GmbH Berlin

City: Berlin | **Country:** Germany

[30/06/2021 – 01/05/2022] **Data Analyst**

Neumann is the de-facto industry standard for studio microphones and I was singlehandedly resposible for data handling, establishing a data-processing pipeline that aggregated, transformed and stored company data in a centralized warehouse, combining purchasing and feedback data for further product decisions

Toolkit:

R, NoSQL, Python, Streamlit, Docker

hubSchrauber

City: Berlin | **Country:** Germany

[31/03/2018 - 30/09/2021] Voluntary Work as Repair Supervisor

At the self-repair workshop Hubschrauber, I helped people repair their bicycles and built up new bicycles from the ground up. Working on a donation basis, hubSchrauber is committed to enabling mobility for everyone, thereby helping in the switch to sustainable modes of transportation.

BMW

City: Munich | **Country:** Germany

[31/03/2017 - 30/07/2017] Project Studies Automated Driving in Urban Business Areas

At BMW I was part of an agile project developing a protoype automated driving solution to enable low-latency remote control of vehicles in a controlled environment. The project successfully proved feasability and its iterations are currently being used.

Technical University Munich

City: Munich | **Country:** Germany

[31/03/2016 - 31/01/2017] **Student Assistant**

As a student assistant with the International Office at TUM, I directly worked with the International student exchange coordinator in managing the exchange program, arranging accomodation, events and taking care of administratorial tasks for over 160 students from more than 33 countries. Flexibility and quick thinking were a necessity for effective solution finding.

EDUCATION AND TRAIN-ING

M.Sc., Information Science at Humboldt University Berlin with a focus on [30/09/2019 - 27/05/2024] quantitative data analytics

Humboldt University Berlin

City: Berlin | Country: Germany | | Final grade: 1.5 | Thesis: Improving Multimodal Large Language Models through metareasoning (in collaboration with the Medical University Vienna)

B.Sc., Management and Technology Oriented Economics with Computer

[30/09/2014 - 09/2018] **Science as a specialization**

Technical University Munich

City: Munich | **Country:** Germany |

[30/06/2017 – 25/02/2018] **Exchange Semester**

South China University of Technology

City: Guangzhou | **Country:** China |

[31/07/2011 - 22/05/2013] **Abitur**

Deutsche Botschaftsschule Peking

City: Beijing | Country: China |

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): German, English

Other language(s):

French

LISTENING C1 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Chinese

LISTENING A2 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

Spanish

LISTENING AT READING AT WRITING AT

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

SKILLS

Python | Microsoft Azure Machine Learning | Machine Learning (e.g. Tensorflow/Keras, Sklearn) | PyTorch | PostgreSQL, Redis, RabbitMQ | Multimodal Large Language Models | Docker | Weaviate | Sentry | Linux | SQL | ELASTIC STACK (ELK) | Microsoft Excel | UML | Git | SLURM HPC | Statistical programming: R programming language | Django Rest FWK | Deepspeed | Java | Aris

PUBLICATIONS

[2023] A comparison of chain-of-thought reasoning strategies across datasets and models

HONOURS AND AWARDS

[20/10/2023] 3rd place at Cloudflight Coding Challenge | Al Awarding institution: CCC

3rd place in Austria / 9th global. Cloudflight Coding Challenge is Europe's largest coding competition.

[04/07/2018] **Best Thesis Awarding institution:** TUM Chair of Research and Science Management

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Personal Interests

When I am not in front of a computer, one can usually find me riding my bicycle. I like to spend my free time reading up on urban planning with a specific focus on sustainable transportation.